- [Robert Jolly] And
WordPress and Accessibility,
so this is something that I'll
cover a bit more in depth,
But I did want to have us go over the
defaults that WordPress has as well as
you know, what's good about Accessibility
in WordPress and why
are we talking about it.
And I see that there was some chat about
the principals and thank
you for posting that link,
Christopher, for folks in the chat.
It's webaim.org, Articles, POUR.
So we'll go there now.
So this is a very good article about
the principals of Accessibility,
that perceivable, operable, understandable
and robust.
So I don't know if you
can see it on my screen,
I'll see if I can zoom
in a little bit here.
But that's an excellent resource.
So WordPress and Accessibility.
There is a commitment within the Core Team
of WordPress to make all of
the new features and functionality
of WordPress from the Core Team to meet
the WCAG 2.0 guidelines at level AA.
So I'm going to zoom in on this right now
and we'll even highlight it for posterity.
Because this is very important.
So they say here, all new
or updated code released
in WordPress must conform with
the Web Content Accessibility guidelines,
2.0 at level AA.
That's great that they say that.
It doesn't always happen
and that is something
that we'll talk about when we talk about
the Gutenberg editor.
I'm sure that folks have heard the
commotion that was stirred up in
the WordPress community when WordPress 5
and Gutenberg first came out.
The Gutenberg team, the Core Team led by
Automatic and folks there you know,
working on WordPress,
they had a number of
known Accessibility issues
that they had decided to launch with
and not address at launch.
And WP campus which is an organization
of higher education institutions
that have come together
to work in WordPress
and to support the WordPress community
for their own needs, but also
for the benefit of others,
commissioned to Gutenberg audit
and the Gutenberg audit listed a number
of problems and a number
of those problems,
with Accessibility, with
the Gutenberg editor,
have been resolved.
There are still a number remaining
and we'll cover that for sure.
But there is a core commitment,
Core Team Accessibility Commitment
and that speaks volumes
about WordPress in general
in terms of what you can
do with WordPress out
of the box with Accessibility.
And we'll get into a tour
of WordPress defaults.
We can certainly do that now,
I wanna open it up for any questions
if folks have them, or any comments
or anything you want us
to dive into more deeply,
before we tour the WordPress defaults.