- Any other items
that you all know about,
that you wanna discuss.
You can look up the term
accessibility in the plugins
directory on WordPress and get
hundreds of plugins, some of
them are really, really good.
Some of them not so much but,
what plugins do you use
for accessible content?
So, there was Deborah, in the chat
posted a link
it's
five awesome
accessibility testing tools
from Claire at A Bright Clear Web.
So
they're talking about
using a screen reader,
using a color contrast analyser,
I'm looking to see if
there are any plugins here.
Looks like there are browser plugins
but I'm not seeing a WordPress plugin yet.
All right.
Karen asks, "Does anyone know of a good
"accessible plugin for charts and graphs?"
That's a great question.
I don't know
of any for WordPress
that do that accessibly.
With Joe Dolsons
WP accessibility
plugin
you can add long descriptions to images.
So, for complex
images
that look like charts
that might be a way to do that.
But if you have
an interactive chart,
something that, you know,
maybe it's drawn via data,
right, coming out of WordPress
and then it needs to be accessible.
That would be something
that I'd need to look at,
to see if there's anything
that's accessible out there.
I don't know of a plugin that will do
accessible charts and graphs just
dedicated to that for WordPress.
SiteImprove, yeah.
So Karen--
Different Karen, Karen with a K,
had asked, are there any
thoughts on site improve?
So,
SiteImprove
is a service,
a software is a service
almost like a third party hosted
place to
run
checks
of your content
both for
SEO content quality,
link validation, things like
that, as well as accessibility.
So,
SiteImprove
is very active
in the accessibility community
and they have a plugin
and we'll talk about that one,
for plugins for actually validating
or checking for accessibility.
It works with their subscription service.
So
I think that could be a valid way
to do checks for accessibility,
it isn't the only thing you should do but,
but definitely there's a plugin for that.
And we'll look at that,
well we'll go ahead and
look at it right now.
While I get a drink of water.
So this plugin, which I haven't used,
I am familiar with folks at SiteImprove
and like them very much, good folks,
but I can't comment on the
the plugin itself,
other than what they say
but it basically allows you to
check your content while
your creating and editing it
and then possibly get
reports in side WordPress
of any scans that SiteImprove does of your
content on your site.
So that's, I wanna see, I
don't think they have any,
they don't have any screen shots there but
basically you have to have
an account with SiteImprove,
it does like they have a free trial so,
it'd be worth checking that out
and seeing what that looks like.
There's another plugin as well
that
we can talk about,
it's called Access Monitor.
So Access Monitor
for WordPress
is built by Joe Dolson
and it hooks into a third party
service called Tenon, T-E-N-O-N
so let
me go to that
and we'll talk about that
because that's another one
where you can check your content
right in WordPress,
for accessibility.
So this one,
it requires an API key
and
it runs
basically this automated scan
and it can
have you
basically check your content
before you're allowed to publish it,
you can have a setting inside of it so,
we can take a look at that when we
get into the testing portion
and we'll test drive that.
So we've talked about child themes
and we've talked about them in relation to
taking an accessibility ready
theme or a commercial theme
and developing
those out
even further and customizing them.
But what about custom parent themes?
Lets talk about those
so what if you wanna build
your theme from scratch?
Lets see.
Lets see if I can find.
So the theme handbook
basically lays out everything
that you can do with a theme
and what are the
building.blocks of a theme.
So I won't get into that in detail but
the process of building a theme can be
from scratch, can be
pretty complex
but this is the part of our
day where we do get into
the complexities of it so,
we have a certain number of required files
that you need to have, you have to have
the index page as well as the
style.CSS.
Then
you have these optional template files,
localisation files and, of course,
with good theme building practices,
you would be separating out your graphics,
JavaScripts, other text files from there.
But
with themes
you have a number of options, right?
You can basically build
your site from scratch
with a theme.
You can make it look any way that you want
and all of those themes
out in the theme repository,
people started from scratch
or from some sort of starter framework
that allowed them to build their own
very own custom theme
to share with others.
So there are,
there are a number of things
that are available to you if you're doing
these custom parent themes.
So, that accessibility ready theme review
that we looked at before.
So these required items
in the theme review
are something that, if
you're developing your
own theme from scratch, even if you're not
publishing it out to the world to share,
if it's something that you
are saying; okay, this is my
custom theme for myself or my client and
I'm not going to sell it or give it away,
then I still highly recommend
you do this
this accessibility ready
required checks for your own custom theme
even if you're not going to
release it into the repository
and get that accessibility ready tag,
because this will make sure that you
have good accessible defaults
built into your theme
where you will need
minimal, if any plugins
to patch accessibility.
So going through this process
is highly, highly recommended
for making any kind of
custom parent theme.
And
lets talk about themes and editing now.
There was one other thing I did want
to talk about besides that--
Well that was the theme guidelines in the
accessibility theme review,
anybody have any thoughts on that?
Do you have a specific
process that you like to use
with custom theme development?
There are just a number of different
starter theme frameworks.
There's underscores
from Automattic
that is fantastic starter framework
that
allows you to build up
your theme from scratch.
So we'll look at that real quick
before I move on to this next section.
So
underscores
dot me I believe is,
yeah, okay so
this site has some contrast issues
as you can see on my screen,
but this is a starter theme for WordPress
and it basically has a whole
lot that it just gives you
out-of-the-box then you
can go and customize
and make your own.
So,
this underscores theme
is a really good starter theme
to then make your own parent theme,
make your own custom theme with it.
But there are a number of other ones too.
I think there's things called Bones,
there's,
of course,
you can start with frameworks
like Genesis Framework
and then create your
own custom child theme
that's much like a parent theme with that.
There are just tons and
tons of resources out there
for having starter files with that,
I think foundations or
foundation has WordPress starter
framework that you can use to
build your own custom theme.
So
go out and do that but
when you do
look at the accessibility ready
required attributes and all
of the documentation here
for getting your theme ready for that tag,
even if you don't submit it
to the theme review team.
If you go through this and
make it accessibility ready,
your users are gonna thank you.