- [Instructor] So, the question is,
does anyone know if screen readers
are sometimes mispronouncing,
or putting unexpected emphasis
on content as it gets read out.
Like, skip to content links, right?
So, the answers is yes,
screen readers still have
that interesting little quirk about them,
where it may say skip to
content, like if you do this,
it's gonna make me content.
And yes, it will, screen
readers will pronounce things
in sometimes unexpected ways,
but as designers and developers,
we don't have to worry
about fixing all instances
of that in some way.
We don't have to jump through
flaming hoops to do that,
because a lot of these are
things that are conventions,
or are very well known
to screen reader users,
and they may even have
changed their settings
to adjust for that,
or they may just have adjusted
their expectations around that,
where if they hear a skip to content link,
and they know it's skip to
the main content, that's okay.
They don't, it's okay that
it's pronounces it that way.
Folks understand how to navigate
using that pronunciation.
So, sometimes acronyms can
get folks into trouble,
and that is where you may,
you may have uppercase text on a page,
and that uppercase text
gets read out phonetically,
or spelled out instead of read as a word.
So, there are some things
that you do need to do as best practice,
but in general,
screen readers do a
really good job with that.
So yeah, we'll take a look
at this real quick, this function.
So, this function...
just changes it.
Instead of skip to content,
it says skip to main content.
Think that's what you were talking about.
So yeah, I mean, you can,
I think that's a valid helper function
that you can have in there,
and make it customizable.
What would be really awesome,
is to allow that to be customizable
through the theme customizations
that you might have with your theme.
So, what do you want that to read out as?
And I think that's
something that Joe Dolson,
with the WP Accessibility
plugin, has allowed people to do,
is to create custom links.
Because there are some sites,
and I'll show one right now.
No endorsement here.
I know people that either
love or hate Starbucks,
but they do a good job
with their skip links.
So, I've just gone to
the site, and I hit tab,
and at first it went
to this exciting updates
to Starbucks rewards.
So, it goes to that promo area first,
but the next tab stop is
skip to main navigation,
then skip to main content,
then skip to footer.
So, people can customize those skip links
and do some interesting
things with them, and really,
you can have more than one area
where you allow people to skip to
if people want to navigate that way.
That's a good use case
for usability testing,
is to find out,
what do people want when
they navigate our site?
And especially if you have
a lot of different areas of the site,
something like this that
I'm showing for Starbucks,
may be super handy to do.
But that is certainly a possibility.
And then, someone asked
about, at some point,
can we go over the reader
mode option in Firefox?
It will basically strip things down,
and I know that we have that reader mode
on our mobile phones as well.
I know, with my iPhone,
a lot of sites will say
there's a reader option available,
and it can strip out ads
and extraneous content.
We can certainly go over that.
I definitely want us to break for a bit.
Let's stop for about...
Well Christopher, what
do you think we should,
how long should we stop for?
And then, return, and then we can return
with that question for the reader mode.