- [Instructor] So let's talk about
content structure, itself.
There's accessible document structure
in pages and posts that
we like to refer to
and that includes a number of things.
So, we have our title,
the title of the HTML page or post.
So, you know, the title of one of my posts
was My Inaccessible Post.
So, that was what goes
inside the title element
and within the head of the document,
and that is something that gets announced
any time that a screen reader
comes to the, to the site
and loads up that page.
That'll be the first
thing that gets announced,
is the page title.
So it needs to be unique and descriptive,
doesn't need to be too verbose,
but it should be unique
for each page of the site.
It should be appropriate for that page.
Then you have headings hierarchy.
So, each page should have one,
and only one,
heading level one.
Then, after that your headings hierarchy
should flow with the natural outline order
of heading level two.
Then if you have another
heading after that
it can be a heading level two,
or it can be heading level three,
but you wanna nest your headings levels
in the logical order.
If your heading levels
aren't in that logical order,
that can cause some problems.
It's probably minor,
as long as you have a
good heading level one
and there's only one of them.
If you have six heading level one's
and they're all different on the page
someone using a system technology
might misunderstand what the
purpose of the page is,
or at least have difficulties
ferreting that out.
Like is it the first heading level one?
Or was that something else?
You know?
What are you using the heading level ones
for if you have that many?
So, its important to think about that
and try as best you can
to keep a logical heading hierarchy
that doesn't skip levels.
Then we have lists.
So, using lists appropriately.
Ordered lists, unordered lists,
as well as definition lists.
Making sure those are used where they are
most appropriate.
And using semantic content for that.
And then tables as well.
So, for tabular data, there are ways
you can mark that up
using divs, and spans,
and most of us have gotten away from
table based layouts.
Using tables for layout.
But, there is a use case for having
data tables on a page,
and understanding how
to put those in place
is incredibly important
for content authors.
So, doing that, and doing that
in an accessible way isn't that hard,
but it just takes a little forethought.