- [Instructor] Let's start talking about
Basic WordPress Customization
for Accessibility.
So, many of you know this.
Some of you may not,
but there are themes that
you install for WordPress
and there is an entire set of themes
that are tagged accessibility ready.
So, the Theme Repository
or the Theme Directory
on WordPress.org
has a series of tags and these
Accessibility Ready Themes
it looks like there are
about 101 of them right now
that you can select and install.
And these are all themes
that are open-source and free
to be able to get into the
WordPress Theme Directory.
So, you can see that
it has the default 2019
that ships with WordPress 5,
but it also has a number of other themes
from third-party developers
that have uploaded them
to the WordPress Theme Directory.
Now, there are standards
and checks that have to be
passed in order for these themes
to get the Accessibility
Ready Tag in WordPress.
We'll cover some of that next.
But we can look at these themes
and you can see this one is called Radon.
And it talks about what it is,
but it has the Accessibility Ready Tag.
It should allow you to create a
very accessible experience.
None of this guarantees that
just because you're going
to use the Radon Theme
that it's going to pass
every accessibility check
with your content.
It just means that it passed the checks
that are in the Theme Developers Handbook
for that particular tag.
And they are extensive checks,
and there's a backlog of themes
that are waiting for people to review them
for the accessibility-ready designation.
I can already see in this screenshot.
It says, Business WordPress Theme
with text over top of an image.
And then it has even smaller text
on top of that image under the
headline, and it's a Carousel
that looks like it has
low-contrast buttons
and the blue is possibly
low contrast on it.
So, there are a number of things
that cause me to think that
this while it is accessibility ready
it would need further customization
to make fully accessible if
I were to use that theme.
So, we have these
Accessibility Ready Themes.
And I talked about this Theme
Review for Accessibility
in the handbook.
So, the required Theme Review
Team, accessibility ready
guidelines here.
So, it takes you through
if you're a theme developer
all of what you need
to do that are required
aspects of your theme.
So, you must have keyboard navigation.
You must have accessible controls.
You must have skip links.
Your forms must
appropriately be labeled and
that they even give you how to test them.
They have information on headings
and reference articles from other folks
to basically
give you guidance on that.
ARIA Landmarks, so I talked
a little bit about landmarks.
So what goes into that
and how do you test it?
Content links and Repetitive Link Text.
It tells you how to use that
screen reader text class, and
make accessible continue reading links
or read more text
with appending the title of the article
into the link
for any continue reading link.
Contrast checks.
Images.
Multimedia.
Has the screen reader text.
And then what is not allowed
for Accessibility Ready Themes.
So, there are just a number of things
that have to go into that.
And then they have a number
of recommended items.
So, having zoomable text.
Make sure the text-only zoom
is enabled with your theme.
Making sure that the text doesn't break,
doesn't overlap when you zoom in.
So, I'm using browser zoom right now,
if you have noticed, and
I'm up to 200% right now.
And nothing breaks on this site, too,
in terms of the layout.
So, I'm able to continue reading this
and demonstrating this.
And the other thing that they recommend
is removing of the title attribute.
So, you notice the media
library had the title attributes
on some of the media items
that I'd imported in.
And those title attributes are repetitive.
And if you have alt text,
you don't need the title attribute.
And some title attributes are just put
onto post titles and into permalinks,
and those can be removed as well.
So, those are certainly
things that you can do.
But the Accessibility Ready Themes
and the process that you go through
to get those passed
and accepted, and have your theme,
have the Accessibility Ready Tag
is fairly, fairly extensive.
They do have a disclaimer here
that the themes labeled
accessibility ready
have met the required
guidelines that are listed
by the WordPress Theme Review Team.
But they don't give you
a stamp of approval,
no formal accessibility requirements.
It doesn't mean that
your theme fully meets
the Web Content Accessibility Guidelines
to at Level Double-A,
it doesn't mean that.
And there are a number of other things
that you'll need to do.
So, does anybody have any questions?
Oh, it looks like if you
remove the title attribute,
will it hurt SEO?
And that's from Kenneth.
I don't believe so.
There are probably better
resources out there,
and certainly Yoast for SEO.
He has an excellent plugin.
So, Yoast SEO.
If we look at that yoast.com,
this would be my go-to resource
for anything SEO-related for WordPress.
There are other SEO
M-O-Z, SEO MOZ, that site
has excellent SEO resources as well.
I believe the title attribute
will not help you with accessibility
when it comes to images.
If you have alt text on the images,
that is picked up by SEO and that will
or by search engines.
And that will help.
The title attribute
could help in some way,
but I think that the negative aspects
of how that is redundant text,
especially for people who have
a verbose screen reader setting.
If the title attribute is
repeated with the alt attribute,
that can get pretty annoying very quickly.
So, those concerns outweigh
any potential benefits
of using a title attribute.
And actually if you're
using an alt attribute
that is in my opinion
better than the title attribute,
just because you're getting that content,
an actual place on the page
versus having the title itself.
The alt is the text alternative
to image-based content.
So, if you're using the alt attribute
and putting that in place,
then that's what you
definitely want to do.
And I have seen where certain plugins
there's a NextGEN Image Gallery Plugin
that is very popular for photographers
and for other highly image-based sites.
And their recommendation
is to use both the
title and alt attribute.
I don't agree with that.
But it is possible that
you could use both.
The title of the page, yes,
Sumner had a great chat answer there.
The title of the page is important to SEO.
That is probably one of the
most important things to SEO.
The title of the page comes up
in your Google results.
So, this is the title
of the page right here,
this Yoast SEO: the Number
One WordPress SEO Plugin,
and then it has a dot
and then Yoast.
So that's the Google
search result listing.
And then the title of
this page is exactly that.
So, in terms of the title of the page,
yes, it's super important for SEO.
But the title attribute,
so there's a title element
and then there are title attributes.
So, if we inspect Yoast's page,
we'll see in the head
this has a page title.
So, this page title is
Yoast SEO: the Number
One WordPress SEO Plugin,
then it has a round dot,
a bullet, and then Yoast.
So that is great.
Now, we'll look and see
if there are title
attributes anywhere else.
Yes, there are somewhere.
Or maybe not, yes, there are
linked titles that are in
oh, that's in the head, too, so.
Yes, so there are some
title attributes that
they're using on links.
And that is something that you can do, but
I wouldn't necessarily
rely on the title attribute
on certain things.
And I'm looking through it here in
in the source code.
And I'm not finding a lot of use
of the title attribute here,
except on iframes.
And so that's good.
So, even their images,
so this Yoast image here
that I'm looking at, oh, that's an SVG.
So, their SVG is a hidden image,
because it's decorative, I
guess, here in this instance.
So, that is a good thing.
So, there's SEO training
and SEO blog here.
I'm gonna look and see if
any of these images
have a title attribute.
These have blank alt attributes, and
looking to see
and they do not use the
title attribute at all.
And they don't use it
on their link as well.
That's probably good advice to follow
is if Yoast is not using
titles for their images
on their site,
and they are the SEO experts,
then I would probably
not use a title attribute
on an image or a link,
unless you absolutely have to.