- [Instructor] So this is
the demo page that Sammy
from the WordPress core team had posted.
So let's see what happens here.
So I'm just going to use my tab.
- [Computer Generated Voice]
Kuorinka, Select City,
pop up button, menu five
items, check mark, Helsinki,
Kuopio, you are currently on a menu item.
To choose this menu item,
press control, option, space.
Press Kuopio, Kuopio,
select city, pop up button.
Filtering contacts was successful.
You are currently on a popup button.
- [Instructor] So filtering
contents was successful.
No where on the page does that say this
in visible text, right?
It is just something that was spoken.
So that is an example of
how that ARIA live region
was populated using the
WP.A11y.speak method
in JavaScript to basically
filter out that information.
So let's see if there's
another thing we can do.
So let's see.
- Accessibility.
Select menu six, up code, money, music,
closing menu, filtering
categories was successful.
You are currently on a pop up button.
To display--
- So there we go.
I filtered y category and it
also announced it, as well.
So that was very, very
interesting how that works.
So with this GABnow site,
they could--
- Voiceover off.
- [Instructor] Start
using a framework to do,
well this is a full page reload.
But if they were doing a
framework to update information,
then they could use that speak method.
Here, here's the accordions.
Let's see if these are accessible here.
'Cause these I know they're accordions
because I can look at job
descriptions under each,
each heading here.
So let's see first if they
are accessible via keyboard.
Let's see.
Oh, I got it to apply now.
It doesn't look like,
back tabbing through all these items.
Yeah, all I can get to are form fields,
and these items right here don't seem
to be keyboard accessible at all.
So that's a flag that
I would throw up here.
But then the other one
would be just to see
what happens with voiceover.
- [Computer Generated
Voice] Voiceover on Safari,
Join Our Team, vertical line, gabnow.org.
Join our team, vericle line,
gabnow.org, web content.
In join our team, vertical,
link, zero, search.
You are currently on a search.
- Notice,
there's no skip link here, as well.
So no way to skip all of
these navigation items.
I just have to go through
them or jump to the region,
which I'll go ahead and
do because I don't--
- Headings Menu.
- Want to go through all that.
- [Computer Generated
Voice] Heading level two,
heading level two items,
volunteer opportunities,
heading level two, heading
level six, two items.
Down pointing black pointer.
Heading level two items, internship.
Heading level two items,
generations against bullying,
GAB, is proud to announce
the following internships available.
Heading level six, two items.
Down pointing black pointer, accounting.
You are currently on heading level six.
Inside of web content.
To exit this web area, press control,
option, shift, up arrow.
- [Instructor] So it just tells me that
I'm on a heading level
six, but it doesn't tell me
that I can do anything with that.
It does say downward pointing black arrow.
On my screen, it's actually green,
but that's the icon that they're using.
It does have for the
symbol that they're using.
And so Safari and voiceover
know enough about this
to say, okay I think that's a
downward pointing black arrow.
But I'm gonna try to click this area
with a control, option, space.
- [Computer Generated Voice] Accounting.
You are currently on a
text element, inside,
down pointing black pointer.
You are currently on a text element, in--
- [Instructor] So now it still
says down point black arrow,
but the arrow is pointing up.
Also, that whole area expanded.
So what I would be expecting
for an accordion control
as a screen reader user would be to know
that something was collapsed
and that it's clickable,
and--
- Karen Creps to everyone,
your video seems to be
lagging behind Robert's audio.
While he was talking about
accord, voice over off.
- [Instructor] So I'm getting
some of the chat come through,
but what I was explaining here was that
the voiceover experience,
or screen reader experience,
I would want that to basically announce
that something was collapsed
and that something was
clickable to expand it.
And I got neither.
In fact, with the way
that this has been coded,
the downward pointing black arrow
is now upward pointing,
but it still announces
as downward pointing black
arrow after it expands.
So while I can click on it with voiceover
because I'm reading through the content,
I just guessed at that.
And that's because I can see the screen
and I know that I can
click on it with a mouse
and do that, and kind
of expand and collapse.
So, there's a little bit of work that
they would need to do here
to make these accordions more accessible.
But they can be, and they can
look the same as they do now.
Other than maybe some color
contrast on their link text,
that looks like it's a light
green or a teal and white.
Which I flag that in
my mind mentally noting
that's something for me to check
and say okay, let's do a full
check on the contrast of this.