- [Instructor] So the Firefox browser
offers a Reader-Mode for websites.
So this can be especially
handy when you're browsing
but there's a lot of dense content,
or a lot of noise even from advertisements
or side-bar widgets that don't really
have anything to do with the article
that you want to read.
So what browser manufacturers have done,
and especially on mobile devices,
is they've enabled this reader-mode
to strip away the superfluous information
or the extraneous information,
that isn't core to what
you're there to read about.
And it can be particularly helpful
when you have ads loading or
auto-playing videos on sites.
Because that can just
destroy the user experience.
So the reader-mode operates
maybe a little bit differently
in each browser implementation.
But the essence is is
that it will try to find
what is the main content of the site
and strip away everything else.
So anything that it knows
is from an ad-network
or from a 3rd-party-call,
it typically removes but it keeps images
if they're in line with the article,
and keeps headings and the
paragraphs that are there.
Which you have to have
good document structure
for that to be present.
So I'm gonna fire-up Firefox,
and this is going to be an
interesting experiment here.
So let me just pull-up a site
where that might be present.
So I'll pull-up a news site,
Washington-Post because I
know that they have ads.
And if I can type and I can get there.
So they have ads, they have videos,
they have like 3rd party content in here.
They have different side-bar
content calls-to-action.
So that is all well-and-good.
But what if I want to read an article?
And let me find something that is...
Okay.
Here's something that hopefully is not as
politically troublesome as some
of the other news articles,
that we see these days.
But see here we have an ad for Google Fi,
up at the top,
and we have this navigation
here called By The Way
which is the section of
the site that we're in.
And then there's a video
and all the content for the article.
And it has some stuff from Twitter
some more ads throughout the site,
you know it's kinda disturbing,
how many ads I'm getting
bombarded with as I view.
But there's this Reader-View
which is fantastic.
So I turn that on and basically,
this strips down the article.
And I don't see any
more ads for Google Fi.
As much as I might love that service,
they're not gonna convince me
by bombarding me like that.
But the article is nice and readable.
It goes into a single column format.
And then we get some other
I guess related articles,
or maybe other different articles
that they're trying to promote,
at the bottom of the article.
But it really simplifies the experience,
and removes a lot of the
clutter and the noise.
On mobile devices it's
something you can easily
do at Safari on an iOS device,
Like an iPhone or an iPad.
And I'm sure that on Android and Chrome,
there are ways to...
You know make the reading
experience easier and better.
So what this reader-mode does for Firefox
and you can change some of
the settings here on the left
but what this does is it can help
with accessibility obviously.
If your eyes are tired,
after a long day of looking at the screen,
like you all are experiencing right now,
changing the background color to Sepia,
and making it less dark of
a contrast with the text,
Can help make the text still readable,
but a little easier on the eyes.
But you know reduce
the eye-strain on that.
You also get rid of all
of this information.
It could be cognitive over-load
for someone with a cognitive issue,
and needs that for accessibility.
So Debra had posted a link.
How to turn on reader-mode
for your browser,
for Chrome, Firefox, Edge,
Opera, and Safari in the chat.
So there's an article that
was recently published
about how to do that.
Which you know we can
all benefit from that.
But there are folks that
will look for the ability
to change the interface in an easy way,
when things get overwhelming.
And I do know of someone who
has a traumatic brain injury,
who really does get overwhelmed
by very busy information on the site.
Or things that change or
get added to the interface
as you scroll-through it,
like all of those Google
ads that we were seeing
in the main article.
So with something like this,
she can go in and click
a button in a setting
and change that experience for her.
So she can dig in and read
the article and focus,
and not get distracted or overwhelmed
by all of that information
that's coming at you at once,
and begging for attention.
So reader-mode is fantastic.
I don't think you have
to do anything special
to support that other than coding
your site with semantics in mind,
giving your site good proper structures
like good landmark information.
Like using the main element
for your main content.
Using a side-elements
for side-bar contents.
Using navigation elements for the nav.
All of those basic html structures,
if you're presenting them to the browser,
the browser will know what to do
to strip-away the extraneous content.
And a lot of this you know happens
with good modern responsive design.
All of this is enabled by that.
So definitely use those best practices.
And the user experience,
that folks who are visiting
your site or using your site,
is going to increase greatly
with the aid of these browser
features and extensions.
Some people also have
their custom style sheets
that strip-away different things.
And they have them for specific sites,
so that they make them more
accessible and better for them.
So user style sheets are something
that will, most likely, always be around.
And while most folks who
use them are advanced,
technologically you know they
are things that people do to,
say change the letter-spacing
or the line-height and line-spacing.
So you know allowing folks to
do that without site-breaking,
is a real art form.