- [Instructor] Using plain language.
So having a logical order on the page
and a logical order within your
your content is key to plain language,
also front-loading important details.
So, in a page title, instead of saying,
my awesome site, colon, home,
say home, colon, my awesome site,
or about us, colon, my awesome company.
So, you front-load
those important details,
that is what someone
with a cognitive issues,
it's going to stick with
them rather than something
that long winded and
finally gets to the point.
Using an active voice whenever possible,
making sure that things
aren't lost in translation
of something that might be
confusing, or confusingly worded,
so you know, using active voice
and using a tool to help you with that,
so there are different services out there
and different interfaces and even plugins
that can help you with authoring
content in active voice,
and even keeping your vocabulary
at a more straight-froward
and simple level.
Using familiar language.
So if your site is
geared towards children,
don't use language that adults would use,
and I'm not talking about foul
language but just, you know,
you don't have to use post-secondary,
or post-graduate level content on a site
that is geared for people
that aren't at that vocabulary level,
or industry specific jargon potentially.
If you're producing a site
that is geared towards kid's health,
or family health topics
for the average individual out there,
not a trained medical professional,
you wouldn't want to use all
medical terminology for things,
you'd want to use
front teeth instead of incisor
or something like that,
or you might want to explain
when you do use technical terms
and use familiar language
whenever possible,
and you want to indicate language changes
wherever possible as well,
so that will help, and that would be
if you're changing langrage
from say, English to Spanish
for a particular piece of content,
that's WCAG requirement to
indicate that programmatically,
but you can also indicate
that in another way as well,
whether that's through a
different text treatment,
if you have a callout
in a different language
then you can treat that differently
and indicate where it might
be helpful for people to know.