- [Instructor] So, you
can find me on LinkedIn.
I quit Facebook and Twitter a while back.
So I've remained on LinkedIn.
I'm under iamjolly,
or you can just Google
Robert Jolly, Knowbility
and you can find me there.
I'd be happy to answer any
follow-up questions there
as well as if you want to
ask questions over Twitter,
or Facebook @knowbility, if you just say,
I'm asking for Robert to chime in on this,
what do you think about this?
Then I'd be happy to get
back in touch with you
through those channels through Knowbility.
So, tea for teaching is one that
that Rebecca had
had asked about.
So the first thing I do when I
load up a page, besides just
visually scanning the page,
is to just start hitting Tab.
So I'm hitting Tab and,
where am I?
Let's see.
Oh, there we go.
Skip to content.
Then Home,
Episodes didn't get, okay.
I don't know if you can see on my screen,
but I'm in the tags, or the
categories, for this posted in
section.
So looking at the focus
outline, I would like for that
to be stronger, for me.
It's also maybe the text size that's
that's getting me a little bit there.
And then,
here we have
I'm in the podcast player interface
which it looks like I can get to
most all of the controls, although,
I don't know when I'm on the Play control.
I think I'm on it now,
so I'm gonna hit the
spacebar to see if I'm on
that button, yes, I am.
- [Video] The student population...
- [Instructor] So I just
hit the button again.
So this doesn't have visible focus on it.
It will hover, and I
can see it turn green,
so I would maybe just add a style to that,
if you're able to control
the styles on these.
Adding a style to allow the focus state
to match the hover state would be
something I would do there.
It's great that you
have a transcript there,
and that just reveals it here.
Not sure if that is
revealed accessibly or not,
so I'm gonna look at it.
I'm just going to Inspect
very quickly and see
so
this is giving a
all right, so that's a list item,
and it says it's already
expanded equals false,
but then the anchor is
what I'm clicking on
and it has a role of
presentation so I'm not,
and it says Transcript.
But it has a role of
presentation so I'm not sure
if that gets announced out.
I would be concerned
about that, but I would
want to check that with the screen reader.
I'm not gonna fire that
open right now to do that,
but I can take a look
at this, and this says
you know, the name is Transcript,
the role is
it says it's the role of
a link here, even though
it's not, but maybe that's
because the container around it
has a tab index of zero,
this list item container.
So this is probably
from a plugin, is what I'm guessing,
because this,
this list item has been made focusable
and been given a role of a tab, on that.
So I would also, yeah,
tab and expanded is not a
thing, that I'm aware of,
so that would be something
I would want to revisit
a little bit with whatever plugin that is.
It may announce out fine,
with a screen reader,
but I would
I would say this is probably
gonna find a couple of issues
if I run fastpass
with that particular tab.
So let's see what happens here.
But keyboard navigation looks really good
overall with that.
No failures detected,
so that's really good.
Some of the stuff that
maybe I was suspecting
and would have verified
with a screen reader,
it may have passed this automated check.
So that's tea for teaching.
Looks like I've got one
I'm gonna take the notary compliance,
Secretary of State, Texas dot gov.
So Texas Notary Public Compliance.
So this is an online training system.
And I'm just gonna do my
thing where I hit Tab.
I don't know where I am
because there's no visible tab focus here.
So that is something I would change.
Now I can just for my testing edification,
I can force tab focus.
Now I am
I am not, okay, so maybe,
yeah, let's see here,
now I can see where I am, at least.
Can I get to?
So I can't activate this menu here,
that apparently I can with a mouse,
so I can't activate the "Need Help" menu.
That would be, that needs
a little help, there.
So I can mouse over it
and it will show up,
but I can't activate it
with a keyboard alone.
And I can't go to that
link, either, directly,
so there's no way for me
to get to this content
or these pages
with that, so that would be
something that I would look for.
I'm not sure if there's a skip link,
doesn't seem like there is,
so I would want one on a site like this,
because you have a number of
repeated navigation items here.
This text may be too low of contrast,
just based on my glancing at it.
It's, it might be fine, though,
it just looks very light on my screen.
So it's 555, which is a dark gray,
against a lighter gray color,
so we're gonna test that right now,
and it's 4.98, so it does
pass the 4.5 to 1 ratio.
It's just, maybe a little light.
So you could, since you're a state agency
that you don't know who is coming to this
you know, obviously, notary publics can be
from all walks of life,
and you will have people who are
of different age, and of
different computer ability.
Making sure that this text
is as legible as possible
is probably quite important.
Because you have some
instructions here where
there are two steps,
first you must do this,
second you must do this,
and, you know, and then
you have some stuff about
you know, logging in and scoring.
This is really important
content, so I would,
I would argue that
make this text both bigger and
and darker, potentially.
So I'm gonna go with
just a plain black text,
and then I'm gonna change its font size
to
3rem, oh, that's too big.
That's downright bad, but you can see
I'm just changing some
stuff in the browser,
and I'm looking at things from
the perspective of
what's going to make this
accessible for people
even if it passes the WCAG guidelines?
Technically, what can make
it even better for folks?
And, you know, those are
the things that I would do
based on just that one home page.
Just look at that menu, change
change the way that this menu works,
there's probably a responsive
menu in here somewhere as well
that might need to be changed,
looked at.
I imagine if I change the size,
yeah, it goes to this
navigation there, and I wonder if that,
yeah, that opens up, but then,
oh, here we go, okay,
I can tab through it.
Can I close it with the escape?
No, but,
can I get to that?
I can't get to the close button, either
with the keyboard, it looks like.
Oh, wait, no, I can.
It's at the bottom.
So this is one where that order is,
it's out of order.
So this x button is up at the top left,
which I would expect to be
first in the source order,
in relation to this home button and also
all of these navigation links,
but it's the last thing on the page,
and then it's somehow
placed at the top,
using CSS.
So I would change that, I think.
And then when this is open,
I wouldn't want to move
people outside of this.
This would be like a modal,
so I would trap people's focus
in here until they explicitly close that,
and then take them back
to this button up here.
So that would be another item where,
controlling where you are,
you know, making sure that
it makes sense for folks,
would be something I would do.
And so how do I force tab
focus, was a question.
I have a bookmarklet.
So there are accessibility
testing bookmarklets
that you can get, and
I'll be sure to add a link to it
in a resources slide, as
well, for later distribution,
but this,
I have two of them.
I have a focus bookmarklet and, I think,
force or show tab focus, but,
but these will basically override
something on a page where
where someone has removed
visible focus but I wanna see it
then I can use that to get around a page
by forcing to show the tab focus.
Now I have it in there twice,
so two orange bars
around these.
So I got double focus.
All right, so captioning is about to end,
in just a few minutes,
so I wanna take a look
at the c-hear dot com.
So here we have some stuff
coming up on the page.
So let's take a look.
So I'm hitting tab and
oh, wait, let's see,
here, I'm hitting tab.
All right, so I've got, all right.
Got some stuff going on here.
Let's see, I'm gonna
just refresh the page,
and then I'm gonna start tabbing.
So skip to content is the
first link, that's great.
Then we have an
accessibility tools item that
animates open, and so it's a widget,
and I can increase the
text, decrease the text,
do stuff with contrast,
do stuff with links,
and fonts, and reset the settings.
So that's cool.
Let's see, hit escape, I
can't close that with escape.
I'd want to be able to do that.
And then there's an
icon with a wheelchair,
so I'm, I guess that
closes it and opens it,
so that toggles it opens and closed.
So that's
should be fine.
Skip to content, and there's a,
there's something that
takes focus up here,
I don't know what it is,
but it takes focus.
It looks like it's a mailto link.
I would want that, if
that is something that
needs to happen, needs to be visible,
if it's in the tab index
then I would make it visible
for folks, as well.
The focus outline is red on blue.
That is probably okay, I'd
wanna check the contrast of that
just to make sure you're
having really good contrast
for those.
Also, you have some hover states
that are really nice.
They kind of animate in,
so the background on the menu changes from
grayish blue, like a gunmetal gray,
to a black background,
when I hover over them,
but all I get when I'm tabbing
is just a red outline.
So I would,
I would keep the red outline,
but I would do that thing that
you do with the hover states
for the focus, to make
them more consistent,
but also more obvious for people who
who have low vision.
Because that little red outline
just might not be bold
enough for some folks.
But I can get to all the links there.
Looks like you have a
YouTube video embedded.
I'm not gonna test that,
but you have read more links
and I'd be interested to see,
hopefully those are
in good context, so I'm
gonna inspect them right now,
and
see what we have,
so all of this looks like
it may be in all a link.
Is that all in a link?
No, okay, so let's go to read more.
Lot of divs here.
So there's a div,
read more, and then there's some
generated content before and after.
That's interesting.
Yeah, I'm not sure how this
would look in a list of links.
So that would be something
that I would wanna know,
like, that these are clearly related to
disability, education, medical, legal,
when you pull up, say, a list
of links in a screen reader.
That would be something
in the learn mores,
the same thing with those.
Then we've got a form here.
Forms are always fun.
These have very low contrast
placeholder text in them.
And if I type in them, the
placeholder text goes away,
so I have to remember,
and if I have a cognitive
disability, that,
I might not remember what this is.
Like, was that industry?
Or was that business that I
just typed in, I don't know.
I have to clear out my,
my information.
So let me see.
I hit the wrong button there.
So one thing I'd wanna check
is the form accessibility here
on these.
Are these labeled appropriately?
They do have placeholder text,
but do they have a label on them?
So I see aria required equals true.
It is using gravity forms
and it is labeled and
oh, wait, the label is
empty.
Oops.
So that might be a problem.
I would wanna check this out
in the accessibility inspector.
So it says, name, first name,
and it's pulling the label
from the placeholder, which is unreliable.
So it doesn't get a label
from the actual label,
it doesn't get it from an aria label,
it just gets it from the placeholder.
So
this would probably be,
I think this would get flagged by a,
an automated checker.
But let me look and see.
All right, and we're
gonna wrap up after this.
So these,
these didn't pick up
those label issues that
I was picking up,
so those may be fine.
I would wanna check that
with the system technology,
though,
make sure that form works well,
but placeholders alone
can be pretty problematic,
so I would recommend not doing that.
Oh, I know why this didn't check.
This caught the labels, but
they have asterisks for them,
so they're not,
they're labeled but they
don't have any meaningful text
in them.
So that would be something
that I would want to
do more about.
So thank you, everyone,
for joining me today.
I hope that the WordPress
information was relevant
and helpful for you.
Please do let me know
what
what questions you have ongoing,
and we will make sure that we get
links to the deck as well
as access to the video
for today's session.