- [Instructor] A common
accessibility issue is disabling
the skip links in a theme.
So we see that quite a
bit where themes override
the skip links.
We see low contrast a lot on
both text and non-text items.
So that's always going
to be a consideration
and something that we need
to look at Alt text issues.
This can be introduced both
from the content authoring aspect,
but also at the theme level,
or plugin level for that matter.
So Alt text issues are
widespread with WordPress sites
and link text problems.
So if you see click here
links or read more links
or continue reading links,
typically those do not get the
appropriate context on them
especially when there's
a list of posts or a grid
of posts that you have
on say an archive page.
And your theme just has a
continue reading or read more
that's repeated for each article.
Those out of context
might be very inaccessible
and confusing for your end users
who are using assistive technology.
And you know maybe they
can't see the connection
between the headline or image of the post
and the read more link.
So there are those link
text problems that we see.
Theme developers often
don't understand the use
of landmarks and appropriate landmarks.
So those create accessibility
problems for folks who want
to jump to say the main area of the page
or get to the widgets or get to,
you know navigation, it's
on the page very quickly.
We also see document
heading structure problems
throughout WordPress sites.
So WordPress gives you
a very liberal interface
for a liberal canvas
for authoring content.
You can create a theme that
restricts that ability, right?
And you can use specific
database fields to then control
how content get entered into WordPress
and then output from it.
But in general, most themes
that you find out there want
to take advantage of giving
authors the most flexibility
with the types of content the structure
of the content, the design so we end up
as a result seeing document
heading structure issues.
So that's something that we'll cover.
And in themes, if you override
the WordPress defaults,
you can lose out on the
language of the page
or if you have say a language switcher,
the language of the parts of the page.
So there are ways to address that as well.
Then we have multimedia.
So multimedia accessibility
problems abound,
not only on WordPress sites,
but across the internet
that can be a range of issues there.
So the multimedia issues
that we see the most
are inaccessible player controls,
as well as video without captions
or with auto generated captions
and audio without transcripts.
So Stephanie had a link in
the chat for a blog post
and I think in the link,
it says it's from 2015.
And the title looks like is why click
here is a terrible link
and want to write instead.
And that's excellent.
I think that's a timeless post.
Sometimes I wish dates
were in those links.
No offense meant to Stephanie
and the link structure here,
but you know this could
be an article from 2006
and it would still be relevant.
So thank you for sharing this Stephanie.