- There were mentions of plug-ins earlier
and there are a number
of plug-is that provide
accessibility or that have
accessibility built in.
So I have an image here of an outlet
that basically transforms a wall outlet
with two power outlets to one with six.
But then there's a seventh power plug that
someone's trying to plug in.
I often feel like WordPress and plug-ins
that's something that is of concern.
How many plug-ins can we possibly need?
There are about 900
billion WordPress plug-ins
it seems not that many but there are
thousands upon thousands if not
hundreds of thousands of
WordPress plug-ins and so you can
over do it with plug-ins.
So what plug-ins are out there?
We'll talk about that.
We'll talk about some really good ones
if you just need something to
start with that will give you
some accessibility support
it won't guarantee things
then we have that.
But a lot like I don't know if
you're familiar with National
Lampoon's Christmas Vacation
but Clark Griswold is the
main character played by Chevy Chase.
One of the things that
he has is he's going for
lights on his house and he wants to
just plug in a million lights
on his house and he has this
one outlet where he has all
of these extension cords plugged
into it with all of these
different splitters and it's
a mess and it's a fire hazard
and it sparks and it throws
the breaker anytime that they
all get plugged in.
But you have to worry about that
in the same vein with WordPress.
Just you know plug-ins can
degrade the performance .
Plug-ins can degrade the
accessibility of your site as well.
So there are you know
sometimes security concerns
with plug-ins.
So choose those wisely.
With that said I'll get
into the heart of this.
So one more note...
I personally feel like we
should not need most of these
plug-ins that we are going to talk about.
I praise the heroes that
made these plug-ins.
They are true accessibility champions.
They are fantastic people
for putting them out there.
But if we develop our plug-ins
and themes accessibly in
the first place then we wouldn't
need these extra plug-ins.
So that's my disclaimer on that.
So this is the granddaddy of all
WordPress accessibility plug-ins.
It's called WP
accessibility by Joe Dolson.
This is something that someone
may have already linked to
but it is something that bears
kind of repeating here as
well as discussing in
detail what it does and
what it doesn't do.
Joe Dolson is a fixture in
the accessibility community
and in particular in the
WordPress accessibility community.
He is one of the leaders of
the team of volunteers that
work on accessibility in
WordPress I worked along side
him on the WordPress accessibility
team for about a year
and he's a great great person.
He speaks at a number of
word camps and publishes this
along with other plug-ins.
So it's WordPress accessibility plug-in
let's look at it.
So what does this thing do?
It adds a certain number of features.
So it will enable skip
links with WebKit support.
So it helps to move the
keyboard focus using JavaScript
with that skip link.
It adds skip links with
user-defined targets
so you can customize the
targets and their appearance.
If your theme has removed
the language attributes and
text direction attributes it will
add them back to the HTML element.
So if you've just got a theme
that your client is in love
with or that you particularly
like but you need to add some
accessibility supports right
away while you're working on
the job theme this is
your plug-in to do that.
It adds outlines to keyboard focus
states for focusable elements,
again this is something
that your theme can do or
your child theme can override.
It can add a tool bar for
toggling between high contrast
large print views of your theme.
I think that's something that
you should use with caution.
You can add a long description
to images and you can enforce
alt attributes on images
which is a really cool thing.
Then some of the things that it fixes.
So it doesn't just add
things it fixes some things.
So it removes the target
attributes from links.
So with the target equals you
know target underscore blank
where it opens a new tab or a new window.
It removes that.
It will remove tab index from elements.
So if a developer has created a theme and
they've used tab index
values indiscriminately or in
earnest potentially but
violating accessibility rules
it will remove that.
It will strip title attributes from
images inserted into content.
So this is related to that question
about you know is that an SCO concern?
Well you know this plug-in is going
to remove it regardless of the SCO
concern but I don't feel
like that's a concern.
It removes redundant title
attributes from page lists,
category lists, and menus.
And it adds the post titles
to the standard "read more"
links so if your theme
developers has just done a
"read more" link but hasn't added
that helper text that we saw in the
theme review guidelines right
for having that contextual
link text then this plug-in will add it.
And it addresses some things
in the admin interface and
it adds labels to the standard
WordPress form fields if they are missing.
It doesn't necessarily fix
every accessibility issue with
forms and validation or things like
that but it will do that.
And then it adds a couple of tools
within your WordPress interface.
So this is probably one of the
go to plug-ins for accessibility
to patch a theme and
some other plug-in based or
plug-in generated or powered
content on your WordPress site.
So this will do it right
away it's not a cure-all for
the problems that might be
inherent in themes that have
accessibility problems and
the goal would be to put
together changes either a
child theme or a custom theme
that gives you what you
want where you don't require
a plug-in like WP accessibility to
run and to fix your content functionality.
So any thoughts or questions on that?
I see someone said, "no plug-in can fix
"all accessibility issues."
That is absolutely true
and that is something that
Joe mentions in his description
in the second sentence here.
While most accessibility issues
can't be addressed without
directly changing your theme, this plug-in
WP Accessibility adds a number
of helpful accessibility features.
So that's something to think about.
It can't correct every problem
by a long shot and yeah
these are things that you'll
see responsible developers
mention when they are talking
about accessibility because
accessibility as you either
know or become more aware
of through this session
it's multifaceted and much
more complex than a binary.
Is it accessible or not?