- [Christopher Schmitt, Moderator]
We had a question about the WordPress
can be used on Safari on Mac
and just wanted, I guess we just should
phrase that that as Wordpress is a CMS
that's hosted on a server,
and the site can be
viewed on any browser.
- [Robert Jolly, Instructor]
Absolutely, yep, yep.
That's a good question.
So, and good answer, so any modern browser
or operating system, mobile or not,
should be able to view
content that you author
in Wordpress.
Wordpress will run on a
variety of server technologies,
but it does require PHP and a database,
usually MySQL or some
MySQL-compatible variant.
Something like MariaDB or even Postgre.
There are ports of Wordpress over to run
on Windows servers, but typically it runs
on a LAMP Stack, which is
Linux, Apache, MySQL, and PHP.
And absolutely, Safari can render content
on Wordpress sites, and I'll
bring that up in Safari now.
And you can author content,
log into the Admin interface,
all of that good stuff in Safari.
So here I have Safari, and
it renders very similarly
to how things rendered
on the other browsers.
And if I go to the Admin page,
I can log in with Safari.
Sure, I'll save password.
And I can get in there and
go to town with doing work.
So I can add a new post
here and add the title.
So yep, absolutely, Safari's
A-OK to author content.
And then I can hit Publish,
and I can go and view
the post, and there it
is, my test post is here.
And it has just an image as the content
because that's what I did as
I was authoring the content.
So I can, I believe I can
inspect as well with Safari?
Maybe I do not have, I may
not have the Safari inspector
active on this yet, but you
can do very similar stuff
with all the browsers that
I was just demonstrating.
And one thing I will do
is we'll test, we'll show
how a screen reader on
the Mac, Voice Over,
works with Safari because
that is the best combination
to test with when you're
testing with a screen reader
on a Mac is to use Safari and Voice Over.
So Jessie asked, "Did
Knowbility choose to focus
"a classroom on Wordpress because we found
"that Wordpress' tools are
more robust for testing
"and checking accessibility
or is it more about
"marketshare going for
potentially the most
"prevalent platform to cover
as many people as possible?"
I think Wordpress is
one of the most popular
and most widely-used CMSs,
content management systems,
and publishing platforms in
use on the Internet today.
The Wordpress community claims
somewhere around 30 percent
or more of the top sites on the Internet
and top millions of sites are
using Wordpress to power it.
So it remains an extremely
popular publishing platform.
It's free and open
source, that is something
that has contributed
to it, but its relative
ease of use for folks
who are non-technical
as well as technically-minded people,
developers and designers,
have fueled its popularity.
So it reaches a vast number of people.
So that we do feel like
is very important for us
to cover a course on Wordpress,
and Wordpress itself has
done a good job overall
in the community of
supporting accessibility
within its platform.
It doesn't mean that things are perfect,
and we'll go over common
problems in just a moment
with Wordpress installs, but
authoring Wordpress sites
does not automatically
mean you're going to author
something that's inaccessible.
It doesn't automatically mean
that it will be accessible,
but it can be, and that's
what we want to focus
on here today is how do
we make the availability
of accessibility in
Wordpress more widely known.
What can you do?
What's out there right now?
What are the best practices?
So certainly the popularity
of Wordpress contributed
to our decision to put
on this course, no doubt.
And most of you in this
session have probably
some familiarity with
Wordpress, might even run
several Wordpress sites.
So that's certainly our target audience,
but if you're new to Wordpress,
this is a good intro I think, as well,
in terms of what do I
need to be concerned with
for accessibility in Wordpress.